Guide to the Wendell Holmes Stephenson Papers, 1820-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches, 1922-1966
  - Book Review: Eaton, Clement-- The Growth of Southern Civilization, 1962, undated (Box 38)
  - Book Reviews: Suggesions for Reviewing a Book, undated (Box 38)
  - Charles W. Ramsdell: Historian of the Confederacy, 1960 (Box 38)
  - The Civil War Centennial: Its Problems and Its Meaning, undated (Box 38)
  - Civil War, Cold War, Modern War: Thirty Volumes in Review, 1959 (Box 38)
  - The Civil War Diary of Willie Micajah Barrow, 1934 (Box 38)
  - Colonel Burke, Big Game Hunter, undated (Box 38)
  - Constitutional and Legal History of England, undated (Box 38)
  - Diplomatic History, 1923-1924 (Box 38)
  - Editor and Contributor, undated (Box 38)
  - The Expansion of the United States in the Caribbean Illustrated by Santo Domingo (Box 38)
  - Foster Prize Essay, 1923 (Box 38)
  - Franklin and Armfield, Slave Traders, ca. 1936 (Box 38)
  - The Friendly Enemy (Diabetes), undated (Box 38)
  - The Good Society, ca. 1965 (Box 38)
  - Harmonious Living vs. Clash and Conflict, undated (Box 38)
  - A Half Century of Southern Historical Scholarship, 1945, undated (Box 38)
  - Herbert B. Adams and Southern Historical Scholarship at the John Hopkins University, 1947 (Box 38)
  - "The Historical Background of Southern Education at Mid-Century," undated (Box 38)
  - History of the South in Colleges and Universities, 1926 (Box 38)
  - Honors Address, Southeastern Louisiana College, 1946 (Box 38)
  - The Influence of Woodrow Wilson on Frederick Jackson Turner, 1945 (Box 38)
  - Introduction of Thomas D. Clark at Mississippi Valley Historical Society Dinner, 1957, May 2 (Box 38)
  - John Spencer Bassett as a Historian of the South, 1948 (Box 38)
  - Mouse Stew, undated (Box 39)
  - The Negro in the Thinking and Writing of John Spencer Bassett, 1948 (Box 39)
  - New Orleans as an Agricultural Focus: Research Notes, 1940, undated (Box 39)
  - Nicaragua and the United States, undated (Box 39)
  - Notes on Anglo-French Relations, 1870-1914, undated (Box 39)
  - Notes on Kentucky Agriculture from the American Agriculturist, undated (Box 39)
  - Origins of St. Patrick's Day, 1942 (Box 39)
  - The Ping, Pang, Pung of a Cuspidorian Orchestra, undated (Box 39)
  - The Political Career of General James H. Lane Prior to His Appearance as a Leader in the Struggle for Kansas, M.A. Thesis and draft, 1924, undated, (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Political Economy, 1922 (Box 39)
  - A Quarter Century of American Historiography, 1958 (Box 40)
  - A Quarter Century of a Mississippi Plantation: Eli J. Capell of 'Pleasant Hill,' 1936 (Box 40)
  - A Quarter Century of Southern Historical Writings, undated (Box 40)
  - Recapturing the Past, 1951 (Box 40)
  - Reviews of Wyllie's Self-made Man in America; The Myth of Rags to Riches, undated (Box 40)
  - Rivalry in the Third-Class Sleeping Compartment, undated (Box 40)
  - The Role of the Editor in Historical Publishing Today, 1951-1957, undated (Box 40)
  - The Role of Youthful Americans in History, in The Eleusis of Chi Omega, Feb. 1966 (Box 40)
  - Roman History, Part I and II, undated, (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Slidell, John, undated (Box 40)
  - Some Pioneer Alabama Historians:
    - I. George Petrie, 1948, undated (Box 40)
    - II. Walter L. Fleming, 1948 (Box 40)
    - III. Thomas M. Owen, 1949 (Box 40)
  - The South Lives in History, 1932 (Box 40)
  - Southern History in the Making: Pioneer Historians of the South (1964): Partial Draft, undated (Box 40)
  - Southern History Class Notes (University of Michigan), undated (Box 40)
  - Speeches:
    - Adventures in Southern History, undated (Box 40)
    - The College of Arts and Sciences: A Statement of Fundamentals, 1941 (Box 40)
    - Columbus [Discovery Day], Northwest Nazarene College, Nampa, Oct. 12, 1954 (Box 41)
    - Editor and Contributor, undated (Box 41)
    - Images and Realities, undated (Box 41)
    - The Ku Klux Klan, Tulane, 1947 (Box 41)
    - Lambda Chi Alpha's Seventh Southwestern Conclave, Baton Rouge, Apr. 17, 1942 (Box 41)
    - Scholarship--Old and New,. Pan-Hellenic Banquet, Mar. 4, 1942 (Box 41)
    - Scholarship in the South, Apr. 23, 1951, undated (Box 41)
    - Some Fundamentals in a College of Arts and Sciences, undated (Box 41)
    - 1920s-1940s, undated, (3 folders) (Box 41)
  - Stephenson, Wendell H.: Clippings, Reviews, and Notices, 1931-1957, undated (Box 41)
  - Tea Time in Merrie England, undated (Box 41)
  - Thomas Hunt Morgan: Kentucky's Gift to Biological Science, 1946, undated (Box 41)
  - The Treaty of Washington and the Geneva Arbitration, undated (Box 41)
  - Tricks on the Dead--And on the Living, The Civil War Cult, undated (Box 41)
  - A Trip into Texas, Letters of P.W. Cram, 1867-1868, 1933 (Box 41)
  - Ulrich Bonnell Phillips, 1939, undated (Box 41)
  - Ulrich B. Phillips: Newspaper Correspondent, undated (Box 41)
  - Ulrich B. Phillips: The University of Georgia and the Georgia Historical Society, 1957 (Box 42)
  - Uncle Leigh and the Goat, undated (Box 42)
  - Understanding the South, 1965 (Box 42)
  - William E. Dodd, Historian of Democracy, 1913-1952, undated (Box 42)
  - William Garrott Brown: Literary Historian and Essayist, 1946 (Box 42)
  - William P. Trent as a Historian of the South, 1949 (Box 42)
  - Zachary Taylor and Richard Taylor, 1935-1936, undated (Box 42)
- Subject Files, 1820-1966
  Correspondence, notes and memoranda, source material, printed material, and writings by various persons relating to Southern history, historians, and scholarly associations. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abernethy, Thomas P., The South in the New Nation, 1789-1819: Draft, (6 folders) (Box 42)
  - Abernethy, Thomas P., The South in the New Nation, 1789-1819: Draft, (4 folders) (Box 43)
  - Adams, Herbert Baxter, 1820-1898 (Box 43)
  - Aeschbacher, W. D. and Mississippi Valley Historical Association, 1956-1966, undated (Box 43)
  - American Association for State and Local History, 1961-1962 (Box 43)
  - American Historical Association:
    - Conference on Televised History Courses for Schools, 1959, undated (Box 43)
    - Meetings, 1956-1961, undated, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Pacific Coast Branch Award, 1952-1957, undated (Box 43)
  - American Historical Association: Reform Movement, 1914-1938, undated (Box 44)
  - Barker, Eugene C.: Southern History and Southern Library Resources, 1912-1918, undated (Box 44)
  - Bassett, John Spencer, and Contemporary Articles, 1892-1918, undated (Box 44)
  - Boyd, Thomas Duckett, 1927-1947 (Box 44)
  - Brown, William Garrott, Southern Tour, 1904, (3 folders) (Box 44)
  - Dunning, William A., 1877-1881, 1954 (Box 44)
  - Fleming, Walter L., 1951-1954, undated (Box 44)
  - Forest History Society, 1956-1965, undated, (3 folders) (Box 45)
  - Frame, Paul N., A Bibliographical Survey of Articles in the Journal of Southern History Volumes I-X, 1935-1944, 1947 (Box 45)
  - Franklin, Isaac, Planter and Slave Trader, 1836-1937, undated, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Guggenheim Grant Application, 1958-1959, undated (Box 45)
  - A History of the South Series, 1942-1951, undated (Box 45)
  - Identifications for Directory of Contributors, 1948-1951, undated (Box 45)
  - Indo-American Congress of American History and Institutions, 1952-1963, undated (Box 46)
  - Institute of Early American Culture, undated (Box 46)
  - Inventory of Manuscripts, 1947-1949 (Box 46)
  - Louisiana State University:
    - Report on Academic Conditions at the Louisiana State University, 1940 (Box 46)
    - Graduate Division of Southern History, 1936-1949, undated (Box 46)
  - Minnesota Historical Society, 1947 (Box 46)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association:
    - Report to Board of Editors, 1952-1953 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1963, undated (Box 46)
    - Membership Committee, 1957, nd. (Box 46)
    - Meetings, 1944-1958, undated, (5 folders) (Box 46)
    - Program Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 46)
    - Report to Board of Editors, 1947-1951, undated, (6 folders) (Box 46)
    - Report of Secretary-Treasurer, 1946-1947, undated (Box 46)
    - Special Committee on the Relationship of the Association to the Secondary Schools, 1957-1958 (Box 46)
  - National Council for Historic Sites and Buildings, 1949 (Box 46)
  - New Orleans History Project, undated (Box 46)
  - Phillips, Ulrich Bonnell, 1901-1905 (Box 47)
  - Phillips, Ulrich B.:
    - Articles, 1904-1929, undated (Box 47)
    - Correspondence of Toombs, Stephens, and Cobb, 1910-1914 (Box 47)
    - Florida Plantation Records, 1925-1928 (Box 47)
    - History of Transportation in the Eastern Cotton Belt to 1860, 1907-1954 (Box 47)
    - Kahn Fellowship, 1929-1931 (Box 47)
    - Life and Labor in the Old South, 1902-1937, undated (Box 47)
    - Life of Robert Toombs, 1910-1913 (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers, 1901-1935, undated (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1903-1925 (Box 47)
    - Plantation and Frontier, 1908-1909, undated (Box 47)
    - Research correspondence, 1905-1954 (Box 47)
    - Yale Period, 1929-1933, undated (Box 47)
  - Research Grants, 1948-1950 (Box 47)
  - Senior, Clarence--University of Puerto Rico, 1947 (Box 47)
  - Southern Biography Series: Reviews, 1940-1941 (Box 47)
  - Southern Historical Association, 1944 (Box 47)
  - Stephenson Family Genealogy, 1941 and 1963, undated (Box 47)
  - Stephenson, Wendell Holmes: Personal Miscellany, 1928-1961 (Box 47)
  - United States Educational Commission in the United Kingdom, 1958-1960, undated (Box 47)
  - University of Michigan: Directory of Ph.Ds in History, 1953 (Box 47)
  - War History Projects, 1944 (Box 47)
- Teaching Material Series, 1923-1967
  The bulk consists of syllabi, tests, bibliographies, lecture notes, assignments, lists of visual aids, and related correspondence for undergraduate and graduate history courses, mostly at the University of Oregon but also at Louisiana State University, Tulane University, and the University of Kentucky. There are also occasional administrative papers. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Air War College, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala., Course 65-1, 1964, undated (Box 48)
  - American Civilization, a Seminar Held at Tulane University, 1947-1948 (Box 48)
  - College Life and Learning, 1956-1965, undated (Box 48)
  - Continuing Executive Committee on the Humanities in Higher Education in the South, 1945 (Box 48)
  - Course Survey, 1966, undated (Box 48)
  - Department of History: Statement of policy in Graduate Work, undated (Box 48)
  - History of the South, Colonial and Antebellum, 1923-1939, undated (Box 48)
  - History 201 (U.S.):
    - Correspondence, 1955-1958, undated (Box 48)
    - Tests, Text, Assignments, Visuals, 1957, undated (Box 48)
  - History 201-202 (U.S.):
    - Discussion tests, undated (Box 48)
    - Objective tests, 1954-1962, undated (Box 48)
  - History 201, 202, 203 (U.S.):
    - Syllabi, 1967, undated (Box 48)
    - TV Illustrations, 1954-1958, undated (Box 48)
  - History 203 (U.S.): TV Lectures, 1958, undated (Box 48)
  - History 202 (U.S.):
    - Seating Chart, 1964 (Box 48)
    - TV Lectures, 1958, undated (Box 48)
  - History 202-203 (U.S.): History Honors, undated (Box 48)
  - History 203 (U.S.): (Box 49)
    - Colloquium, 1967 (Box 49)
    - Objective Tests, 1959, undated (Box 49)
    - Special Session, 1964 (Box 49)
    - Tests, 1967, undated (Box 49)
  - History 408, Syllabus and Invitations, 1966, undated (Box 49)
  - History of the South, Class Notes, 1923-1924 (Box 49)
  - History 457, 458, 459: Tentative Syllabus, undated (Box 49)
  - History 507 (Era of the Civil War): Bibliography, undated (Box 49)
  - History 520: Selected Readings, undated (Box 49)
  - History 617-618 (The South): Syllabi, undated (Box 49)
  - Louisiana State University, 1934-1939 (Box 49)
  - NROTC: Tentative Curriculum for Marine Courses, 1947 (Box 49)
  - Old South: Syllabi and Tests, 1937-1948, undated (Box 49)
  - Suggestions and Instructions for Historical Research and Writing, undated (Box 49)
  - Tulane University:
    - Honor System, 1947-1951 (Box 49)
    - Latin American Studies, 1948, undated (Box 49)
    - Reserved Book List, 1945-1949, undated (Box 49)
    - Social Science Faculty Members, 1947, undated (Box 49)
    - Tulane Historical Society, 1948-1950, undated (Box 49)
    - Work Conference for the Training of College Teachers, 1951-1952, undated (Box 49)
  - U.S. History, 1492-1840, Notes, undated (Box 49)
  - University and College Education, 1947 (Box 49)
  - University of Oregon:
    - Joan Rieff, undated (Box 49)
    - Sabbatical Leave, 1959-1960 (Box 49)
- Journal of Southern History: Correspondence, 1854-1943, bulk, 1928-1943
  Mostly correspondence with scholars, students, librarians, publishers, and historical organizations concerning Journal articles and business, activities of historical associations, research and publication projects, and the careers of students and teachers. The files sometimes contain printed material and manuscripts of articles. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Ad-Au, 1930-1941, undated (Box 50)
  - A. N. Marquis Co., 1940-1941, undated (Box 50)
  - Abbey, Kathryn T., 1935-1941, undated (Box 50)
  - Abernethy, Thomas P., 1934-1942, undated (Box 50)
  - Adams, George, 1938-1942, undated (Box 50)
  - Adams, Horace, 1937-1940, undated (Box 50)
  - Adams, Randolph G., 1936-1941 (Box 50)
  - Adler, Selig, 1940-1941 (Box 50)
  - Advertising, 1935-1942, undated (Box 50)
  - Affleck, T. D., 1934-1942, undated (Box 50)
  - Agricultural History Society, 1919-1942, undated (Box 50)
  - Alabama State Department of Archives and History, 1934-1941, undated (Box 50)
  - Albion, Robert C., 1940-1942 (Box 50)
  - Alexander, Edward P., 1938-1939 (Box 50)
  - Allen, Winnie, 1937-1939 (Box 50)
  - Ambler, C. H., 1936-1941 (Box 50)
  - American Historical Association, 1928-1941, undated, (2 folders) (Box 51)
  - American News Company, Inc. 1935-1941 (Box 51)
  - Ames, Susie M., 1940-1943 (Box 51)
  - Anderson, Russell H., 1938-1941 (Box 51)
  - Andreasson, John, 1936-1942 (Box 51)
  - Andrews, Matthew P., 1937-1939 (Box 51)
  - Andrews, Rena M., 1936-1937 (Box 51)
  - Angle, Paul M., 1934-1937 (Box 51)
  - Announcements, Southern Historical Review, 1934-1935, undated (Box 51)
  - Appleton-Century Company, 1934-1942, undated (Box 51)
  - Arnett, Alex M., 1937-1939 (Box 51)
  - Arthur H. Clark Co., 1935-1941, undated (Box 51)
  - Arthur, Stanley Co., 1936-1940, undated (Box 51)
  - Ashe, Samuel A., 1935-1938, undated (Box 51)
  - Atherton, Lewis, E., 1938-1941, undated (Box 51)
  - Bab-By, 1935-1943, (4 folders) (Box 51)
  - Barker-Crothers, Hayes, 1935-1942, undated (Box 51)
  - Baringer, William E., 1937-1940, undated (Box 51)
  - Barker, Charles A., 1935-1941, undated (Box 52)
  - Barnhart, John D., 1935-1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 52)
  - Barnwell, Robert W., 1940-1942 (Box 52)
  - Bartlett, Ruhl J., 1934-1938 (Box 52)
  - Beale, Howard K., 1939-1943 (Box 52)
  - Bedsole, Virgil L., 1939-1941 (Box 52)
  - Bettersworth, John K., 1937-1941 (Box 52)
  - Biesele, R. L., 1934-1941 (Box 52)
  - Binkley, W. C., 1934-1943, undated, (3 folders) (Box 52)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1934-1941, undated (Box 52)
  - Bolton, Herbert E., 1936-1939 (Box 52)
  - Bonham, Milledge L., Jr., 1935-1940, undated (Box 52)
  - Books for Review, Requests for, 1938-1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 53)
  - Bourne, Henry E., 1933-1936 (Box 53)
  - Boyd, William K., 1934-1938 (Box 53)
  - Bramlette, David C., 1938 (Box 53)
  - Brand, Donald D., 1938-1940 (Box 53)
  - Bruce, Kathleen, 1935-1938 (Box 53)
  - Buck, Paul H., 1938-1942, undated (Box 53)
  - Burdine, J. Alton, 1934-1935 (Box 53)
  - Burnett, Edmond C., 1936-1941 (Box 53)
  - Ca-Cu, 1934-1943, (2 folders) (Box 53)
  - Cabaniss, Allen, 1940-1941, undated (Box 53)
  - Caldwell, Norman W., 1939-1941, undated (Box 53)
  - Campbell, Rachel, 1940, undated (Box 53)
  - Campbell, E. G., 1938-1940 (Box 53)
  - Capers, Gerald M., 1937-1941 (Box 53)
  - Cappon, Lester J., 1935-1942, undated (Box 53)
  - Cardwell, J. A., 1942-1943 (Box 54)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1937-1942 (Box 54)
  - Carroll, H. B., 1941-1942 (Box 54)
  - Carsel, Wilfred, 1939-1940, undated (Box 54)
  - Carter, Clarence E., 1937-1941 (Box 54)
  - Case, Lynn M., 1934-1940 (Box 54)
  - Castaneda, C. E., 1936-1942, undated (Box 54)
  - Cate, Wirt Amistead, 1935-1942 (Box 54)
  - Cawthon, John A., 1935-1939 (Box 54)
  - Caxton Printers, 1936-1941, undated (Box 54)
  - Chamness, Ivy L., 1934-1940 (Box 54)
  - Chitwood, Oliver P., 1937-1941 (Box 54)
  - Clark, Blanche Henry, 1942 (Box 54)
  - Clark, John P., 1937-1941 (Box 54)
  - Clark, Thomas D., 1936-1942, undated (Box 54)
  - Cleworth, Marc M., 1938 (Box 54)
  - Cline, Pierce, 1933-1935 (Box 54)
  - Coddington, Edwin B., 1938-1941 (Box 54)
  - Cole, A. C., 1934-1940 (Box 54)
  - Cole, Fred, 1941-1942, undated (Box 54)
  - Cole, Taylor, 1939 (Box 54)
  - Coleman, Christopher B., 1936-1940, undated (Box 54)
  - Coleman, J. Winston, Jr., 1938-1942 (Box 54)
  - Coleman, James K., 1936-1937 (Box 54)
  - Coleman, William A., 1939 (Box 54)
  - College Catalogs, 1939-1940, undated (Box 54)
  - Columbia University Press, 1935-1941, undated (Box 54)
  - Committee on Speakers and Conferences, Louisiana State University, 1939-1941, undated (Box 54)
  - Connor, R. D. W., 1935-1937 (Box 54)
  - Copyright Office--Library of Congress, 1935-1942 (Box 54)
  - Corbitt, D. C., 1940-1941 (Box 54)
  - Cordle, C. G., 1937-1942, undated (Box 54)
  - Cotterrill, R. S., 1935-1942, undated (Box 54)
  - Coulter, E. Merton, 1934-1941, undated (Box 55)
  - Cox, I. J., 1935-1942 (Box 55)
  - Craven, Avery O., 1937-1942 (Box 55)
  - Craven, Wesley F., 1936-1941 (Box 55)
  - Crenshaw, Ollinger, 1931-1942 (Box 55)
  - Crittendon, C. C., 1935-1942 (Box 55)
  - Crowley the Magazine Man, 1936 (Box 55)
  - Cumming, W. R. P., 1937-1938, undated (Box 55)
  - Dab-Dy, 1935-1943, undated, (2 folders) (Box 55)
  - Dale, E. E., 1939-1943 (Box 55)
  - Dauer, Manning J., 1939-1940 (Box 55)
  - Davenport, F. G., 1936-1941, undated (Box 55)
  - Davidson, Chalmers G., 1940-1941 (Box 55)
  - Davidson, Philip, 1935-1942, undated (Box 55)
  - Davis, Charles S., 1924-1942 (Box 56)
  - Davis, Richard Beale, 1940-1941 (Box 56)
  - Dempsey, Elam F., 1935-1939, undated (Box 56)
  - Destler, Chester, 1937-1940 (Box 56)
  - Diamond, William, 1938-1940, undated (Box 56)
  - Dictionary of American Biography, 1929-1937, undated (Box 56)
  - Dictionary of American History, 1936-1940, undated (Box 56)
  - Dietz Printing Company, 1935-1942 (Box 56)
  - Donnan, Elizabeth, 1935-1940 (Box 56)
  - Dooley, Oscar, 1937-1938 (Box 56)
  - Dorris, J. T., 1934-1941, undated (Box 56)
  - Downes, Randolph C., 1936, undated (Box 56)
  - Downum, Garland, 1938 (Box 56)
  - Drake, Julia A., 1938-1939 (Box 56)
  - Drell, Bernard, 1938 (Box 56)
  - Duke University Press, 1935-1942, undated (Box 56)
  - Dumond, Dwight, 1934-1942 (Box 56)
  - Duniway, David C., 1939 (Box 56)
  - Dunn, F. Roger, 1937-1941 (Box 56)
  - Dyer, J. P., 1938-1942, undated (Box 57)
  - Dykstra, Charles, 1938-1940 (Box 57)
  - Ea-Ew, 1934-1943, undated (Box 57)
  - East Tennessee Historical Society, 1935 (Box 57)
  - Easterby, J. H., 1936-1941, undated (Box 57)
  - Eaton, Clement, 1935-1941, undated (Box 57)
  - Edwards, Everett E., 1938-1942, undated (Box 57)
  - Elliott, Claude, 1938-1942, undated (Box 57)
  - Ellis, Elmer, 1935-1939 (Box 57)
  - Englesman, John, 1938-1941 (Box 57)
  - Erickson, Edgar L., 1937-1941 (Box 57)
  - Exchanges, 1935-1941, undated (Box 57)
  - Fa-Fr, 1935-1943, undated (Box 57)
  - F. W. Faxon Co., 1935-1942 (Box 57)
  - Fant, H. B., 1936-1938, undated (Box 57)
  - Farish, Hunter D., 1935-1942 (Box 57)
  - Fellowship Applications, 1936 (Box 57)
  - Ferguson, R. J., 1935-1941 (Box 57)
  - Ferguson, W. C., 1937 (Box 57)
  - Field, Alston G., 1936-1938, undated (Box 57)
  - Flanders, Ralph B., 1935-1942 (Box 57)
  - Fleming, Walter L., 1937-1941, undated (Box 57)
  - Florida Historical Society, 1936-1942 (Box 57)
  - Folmsbee, S. J., 1935-1941 (Box 58)
  - Forbes, Gerald, 1937-1943 (Box 58)
  - Fox, Early, 1936-1938 (Box 58)
  - Franklin, Isaac, 1931-1938 (Box 58)
  - Franklin, W. Neil, 1935-1942, undated (Box 58)
  - Franklin Press, 1935-1942, undated (Box 58)
  - Franklin Square Agency, 1935-1941, undated (Box 58)
  - Fraser, Jessie M., 1935-1941, undated (Box 58)
  - Frederick, J. V., 1938-1939 (Box 58)
  - Freeman, Douglas S., 1934-1940 (Box 58)
  - Frey, Fred C., 1938-1941, undated (Box 58)
  - Fuller, J. P. D., 1934-1936 (Box 58)
  - Ga-Gu, 1854, 1934-1942 (Box 58)
  - G. E. Stechert and Co., 1935-1942 (Box 58)
  - Gambrell, Herbert P., 1935-1938 (Box 58)
  - Garber, Paul Neff, 1938-1942 (Box 58)
  - Garner, James W., 1937-1938 (Box 58)
  - Garrett and Massie, Inc., 1934-1940, undated (Box 58)
  - Garrison, Curtis W., 1937-1941, undated (Box 58)
  - Gates, Paul W., 1936-1942, undated (Box 59)
  - Gerald, Leo, 1935-1941 (Box 59)
  - Gilbert, Felix, 1940-1942 (Box 59)
  - Glennon, John F., 1935 (Box 59)
  - Glunt, James D., 1935-1940 (Box 59)
  - Govan, Thomas P., 1937-1942 (Box 59)
  - Green, E. L., 1936-1937, undated (Box 59)
  - Green, Fletcher M. and Southern Historical Association, 1934-1942, undated, (4 folders) (Box 59)
  - Green, Philip J., 1936 (Box 59)
  - Greer, James K., 1936-1937 (Box 60)
  - Gregorie, Anne, 1938-1941 (Box 60)
  - Grigsby, Robert W., 1937-1938 (Box 60)
  - Gruss, Louis, 1939-1940 (Box 60)
  - Guyton, Pearl, 1940, undated (Box 60)
  - Hac-Hy, 1934-1942, (3 folders) (Box 60)
  - H. W. Wilson and Co., 1939-1940 (Box 60)
  - Haggard, J. V., 1942, undated (Box 60)
  - Hamlin, C. H., 1937-1938 (Box 60)
  - Haley, J. Evetts, 1934-1935 (Box 60)
  - Halsell, W. D., 1939-1941 (Box 60)
  - Hamer, Marguerite, 1935-1939, undated (Box 60)
  - Hamer, Philip May, 1934-1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 60)
  - Hamilton, J. G., de Roulhac, 1937-1941, undated (Box 60)
  - Hamilton, William B., 1935-1941, undated (Box 60)
  - Hanna, A. J., 1936-1941 (Box 60)
  - Hanson-Bennett Magazine Agency, 1936-1941 (Box 60)
  - Harcourt, Brace, and Co., Inc., 1934-1941 (Box 60)
  - Hardie, Ann Smith, 1936-1937 (Box 60)
  - Harper, Roland, 1930-1937 (Box 60)
  - Harrington, Fred H., 1938-1941 (Box 60)
  - Harrison, Fairfax, 1933-1935, undated (Box 60)
  - Harwell, R. B., 1940-1942 (Box 61)
  - Hatcher, W. B., 1936-1941, undated (Box 61)
  - Hay, T. R., 1935-1942, undated (Box 61)
  - Hayes, Webb C., 1939-1941 (Box 61)
  - Hebert, Paul M., 1939-1941 (Box 61)
  - Helderman, L. C., 1935-1936, undated (Box 61)
  - Hemphill, Edwin, 1939-1941 (Box 61)
  - Henderson, Archibald, 1936-1940, undated (Box 61)
  - Henderson, Gavin B., 1938-1941, undated (Box 61)
  - Henry, Cammie Garrett, 1941 (Box 61)
  - Herdman, Margaret M., 1936 (Box 61)
  - Herman Goldberger Agency, 1935-1936 (Box 61)
  - Herold, Virginia Lee, 1935-1936, undated (Box 61)
  - Herring, Harriet L., 1937-1938 (Box 61)
  - Hesseltine, W. B., 1934-1941 (Box 61)
  - Hicks, John D., 1938-1941 (Box 61)
  - Higginbotham, S. W., 1939-1942, undated (Box 61)
  - Hill, Louise Biles, 1935-1939 (Box 61)
  - Hill, Roscoe R., 1939 (Box 61)
  - Hilldrup, R. L., 1936-1937, undated (Box 61)
  - History of the South series, 1937-1943, undated (Box 61)
  - Hodges, Campbell B., 1942-1943, undated (Box 61)
  - Hogan, William R., 1935-1940, undated (Box 62)
  - Holmes, Alester G., 1937-1940 (Box 62)
  - Holt, William S., 1931-1942, undated (Box 62)
  - Holt, Henry and Co., Inc., 1934-1941 (Box 62)
  - Holton, Holland, 1938-1940 (Box 62)
  - Honeycutt, W. C., 1935-1938 (Box 62)
  - Hopkins, Garland E., 1939-1942, undated (Box 62)
  - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1934-1940, undated (Box 62)
  - House, Albert V., Jr., 1937-1941, undated (Box 62)
  - Houston, G. O., 1935-1936 (Box 62)
  - Howard, Clinton N., 1938-1940 (Box 62)
  - Hubbell, Jay B., 1938-1942 (Box 62)